<resources>
    <!-- License -->
    <string name="history_photo">History photo</string>

    <string name="app_name">BulgariaTour</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="nav_header_title">Bulgaria Tour</string>
    <string name="title_activity_places_list">Places</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detail">Detail</string>

    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">http://www.bulgariatravel.org/bg</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_image">title image</string>

    <string name="dummy_content">Dummy content</string>
    <string name="detail_image">detail_image</string>

    <!-- Mountain BURGAS -->
    <string name="bourgas">Bourgas</string>
    <string name="island_anastasia">Island world Anastasia</string>
    <string name="island_anastasia_detail">St. Anastasia Island, formerly called Bolshevik Island,
        is a Bulgarian islet in the Black Sea.\n It is located 1.5 km off the coast near Chernomorets,
        at 12 metres above sea level, and covers a territory of one hectare.\t It is the only
        inhabited island off the Bulgarian Black Sea Coast.The island is supplied with electricity
        and drinking water. It is named after the former St. Anastasia convent located on it.\t
        The convent had existed since the Middle Ages and was reconstructed during the 18th-19th
        century. It has been abandoned since 1923, when the island was transformed into a prison.
        Today, in addition to the monastery with its church, there is a lighthouse situated on the
        island, as well as a museum, a restaurant, a small quay, a conference hall and two
        guesthouses with a total of five rooms available to tourists. In the summer, the island is
        accessible from Burgas via boat services running back and forth multiple times a day.\n
        Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="burgas_port_detail">Port of Burgas is the Bulgarian port. It is well-established
        as the Trans-European Ten-T Trans-European Transport Network. Situated in the bay of the
        same name in the westernmost part of the Black Sea coast of Burgas, the port has a total
        of 19 ship sites with a maximum allowable water catchment of 12.3 m.  Port Bourgas is part
        of the Bourgas Port District, which covers the area from Cape Emin to Rezovska River and
        includes a total of 8 (state and private) port operators: Port Bourgas, Port Rosenets-Lukoil
        Neftochim, BMF Port Bourgas, Dockyard Port Bourgas, Fishport, , Liberty Port, Nesebar
        terminal.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="sea_beach">Sea beach</string>
    <string name="sea_beach_detail">The beach of Kraimorie attracts many tourists mostly because of
        its sand - mild, golden and without stones. The beach itself is long but narrow. The water
        is shallow and the seabed is sloping and without drastic changes in depth. Part of the beach
        is guarded by lounges and umbrellas. Kraimorie Beach is quiet and there are campsites,
        restaurants, shops, bars and family hotels in the vicinity, and free parking is provided for
        the convenience of the beachmen.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="night_city">Night_city</string>
    <string name="night_city_detail">Nightlife is most interesting part, here can be found original
        places, symbols of the nightlife. Bourgas, is one of the cities in Bulgaria with the
        strongest nightlife. Although it is a summer tourist destination for the sea, here you will
        find quality entertainment throughout the year. If you are from Burgas - comment on the
        selection and keep us informed about the changes in your preferences. Night life is not a
        good life, but it\'s my life.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="light_house">Beach Light House</string>
    <string name="old_fasion_trail_detail">Burgas Central railway station (Tsentralna zhelezopatna
        gara Burgas) is the main station serving the Black Sea city and municipality of Burgas, the
        fourth most populous city, and the largest and most important port, in Bulgaria.Opened in
        1903,[1] the station is the terminus of the line from Karnobat, which links Burgas with the
        rest of Bulgaria rail network. \n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>
    <string name="sunrise_in_burgas">Sunrise in Burgas</string>
    <string name="old_fasion_trail">Old fashion trail</string>

    <!-- Mountain RILA -->
    <string name="rila">Rila</string>
    <string name="mountain_rila">Mountain Rila</string>
    <string name="rila_lakes">The Seven Rila Lakes (Bulgarian: Седемте рилски езера, transliterated:
        Sedemte rilski ezera) are a group of glacial lakes, situated in the northwestern Rila
        Mountains in Bulgaria. They are the most visited group of lakes in Bulgaria. The lakes are
        situated between 2,100 and 2,500 metres elevation above sea level.  Each lake carries a name
        associated with its most characteristic feature. The highest one is called Salzata
        (\"The Tear\") due to its clear waters that allow visibility in depth. The next one in
        height carries the name Okoto (\"The Eye\") after its almost perfectly oval form. Okoto is
        the deepest cirque lake in Bulgaria, with a depth of 37.5 m. Babreka (\"The Kidney\") is the
        lake with the steepest shores of the entire group. Bliznaka (\"The Twin\") is the largest
        one by area. Trilistnika (\"The Trefoil\") has an irregular shape and low shores. The
        shallowest lake is Ribnoto Ezero (\"The Fish Lake\") and the lowest one is Dolnoto Ezero
        (\"The Lower Lake\"), where the waters that flow out of the other lakes are gathered to form
        the Dzherman River.  The Seven Lakes are a tourist attraction in Bulgaria because of its
        natural environment. The lakes are located one above the other and are connected by small
        streams, which form tiny waterfalls and cascades. Tourist accommodation in the lakes\'
        vicinity include a chalet on the northeastern shore of The Fish Lake, at an elevation of
        2,196 m.[citation needed] The most common time to visit the lakes is summer, in July and
        August, when temperature is above 10 degrees Celsius and the risk of sudden storms is lower.
        [citation needed] During the rest of the year the weather can be severe.[citation needed]
        The lakes usually freeze during October, and do not melt before June. The ice cover can
        reach up to 2 meters.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="seven_rila_lakes">Seven Rila Lakes</string>
    <string name="rila_mountain">Rila (Bulgarian: Рила, pronounced [ˈriɫɐ]) is a mountain range in
        southwestern Bulgaria and the highest mountain range of Bulgaria and the Balkans, with its
        highest peak being Musala at 2,925 m. The massif is also the sixth highest mountain in
        Europe (when each mountain is represented by its highest peak only), coming after the
        Caucasus, the Alps, Sierra Nevada, the Pyrenees and Mount Etna, and the highest between the
        Alps and the Caucasus. More than one-third of the mountain is occupied by the Rila National
        Park, the rest lies within the Rila Monastery Nature Park.  The mountain is believed to have
        been named after the river of the same name, which comes from the Old Bulgarian verb \"рыти\"
        meaning \"to grub\".[1][2]  Rila is abundant in glacial lakes (about 200) and hot springs in
        fault areas at the base of the mountain. Some of the Balkans\' longest and deepest rivers
        originate from Rila, including Maritsa, Iskar and Mesta.  Culturally, Rila is famous for the
        Rila Monastery, Bulgaria\'s largest and most important monastery, founded in the 10th
        century by Saint John of Rila. Alongside the cultural landmarks the mountain is also famous
        for the Seven Rila Lakes.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="malyovitsa_rila">Malyovitsa  mountain</string>
    <string name="rila_malyovitsa">Malyovitsa is a peak and ski resort in the northwestern part of
        the Rila Mountains in southwestern Bulgaria. It is 2,729 m high and is one of the most
        popular tourist regions in the mountain. The Rila Monastery is situated at its southern foot,
        and Malyovitsa Ski Centre with two downhill tracks and two ski drags is to the north. The
        main starting point for treks in the region is Malyovitsa Hut (at about 2 hours walk from
        the top of the summit).  The Malyovitsa region is the cradle of Bulgarian rock climbing and
        mountaineering. The first organized expeditions were made in 1921–22 by tourists from the
        town of Samokov. The imposant north wall of the summit was first climbed in 1938 by
        Konstantin Savadzhiev and Georgi Stoimenov (about 200 m). That was the greatest success of
        Bulgarian climbers for its time and is deemed as the date of birth of Bulgarian
        mountaineering. Later other walls in the region were climbed too with the most difficult
        routes being made in the 1970s. In the last 15 years, Malyovitsa region has become very
        attractive rock climbing district with the possibilities it gives for mountaineering and
        sport rock climbing.  Other interesting walls and summits are: Zliya Zab (200 m wall with
        one of the most famous climbing routes in the country, Vezhdite), Dvuglav (a 450 m high wall,
        with climbing routes often over 500 m long), Iglata, Dyavolski Igli (several aretes with the
        hardest climbs in the region), Ushite and others. A wall that is available for not so
        experienced rock climbers is Kuklata. It is situated across Malyovitsa hut, 10 minutes
        walking, and the main part of its tours is bolted.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="monastery_rila">Rila Monastery</string>
    <string name="rila_monanstery">The Monastery of Saint Ivan of Rila, better known as the Rila
        Monastery (Bulgarian: Рилски манастир, Rilski manastir) is the largest and most famous
        Eastern Orthodox monastery in Bulgaria. It is situated in the southwestern Rila Mountains,
        117 km (73 mi) south of the capital Sofia in the deep valley of the Rilska River at an
        elevation of 1,147 m (3,763 ft) above sea level, inside of Rila Monastery Nature Park. The
        monastery is named after its founder, the hermit Ivan of Rila (876 – 946 AD), and houses
        around 60 monks.  Founded in the 10th century, the Rila Monastery is regarded as one of
        Bulgaria\'s most important cultural, historical and architectural monuments and is a key
        tourist attraction for both Bulgaria and Southern Europe. In 2008 alone, it attracted
        900,000 visitors.[1] The monastery is depicted on the reverse of the 1 lev banknote, issued
        in 1999.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="panicata_lake">Panicata Lake</string>
    <string name="rila_panicata_lake">The Urdini lakes are a lake group with glacial origin in the
        Rila Mountains. They are not developed as a tourist attraction as well as the Seven Rila
        Lakes because they are situated in the most difficult parts of the Northwest Rila. Urdina
        lakes are located in the western part of the Urdina cirque between Mount Dumbha (2670 m) to
        the northwest and Dodov peak (2661 m) to the south. They are six in number and have the
        following names: Dry, Fish (not to be confused with the Lake of the Seven Lakes), Triangle,
        Botanical, Big Panite and Little Panic. Urdina River, which is the right tributary of the
        Cherni Iskar River, runs out of Urdina lakes.  The lakes have a relatively small area - from
        0.8 to 2.5 hectares. At least in area is the Fish Lake (at 2348 m above sea level), which
        due to its proximity to the peak of Damga (about 500 m southeast of the peak) is also called
        Damsko Lake. Although the Fish Lake is the smallest in size, it has the largest catchment
        pool in the group. The lowest lake, Big Panitza (42 ° 10\'39 \"N 23 ° 19\'45\" E), is also
        the largest area and volume of water in it. It is situated at 2278 m above sea level, has
        an area of ​​about 2.5 hectares and a water volume of approximately 89,500 m 3.  The shores
        of the individual Urdini lakes are varied. The highest lake of the Suhoto group (42 ° 10\'28
        \"N 23 ° 19\'44\" E) is located not far from Dodov peak and is 2375 m above sea level. The
        lake has a circular shape and is about 5 m deep. The deepest (7.6 m) is the fourth small
        lake (2336 m) and is located east of the Ribnoto. The water flowing out of it forms a small
        waterfall before it flows into the Great Plain Lake and then into the Urdina River.  In 1985,
        Urdini Lakes were declared a natural landmark of national and international importance. The
        lakes are loaded with rainbow and Balkan trout, making them an attractive place for poachers.
        Fishing is forbidden.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>


    <!-- Mountain PIRIN -->
    <string name="pirin">Pirin</string>
    <string name="mountain_pirin">Pirin Mountain</string>
    <string name="pirin_mountain">The Pirin Mountains (Bulgarian: Пирин) are a mountain range in
        southwestern Bulgaria, with Vihren at an altitude of 2,914 m being the highest peak. One
        hypothessis is the mountain was named after Perun, the highest god of the Slavic pantheon
        and the god of thunder and lightning. Another version is that the etymology of the range
        derives from the Thracian word Perinthos, meaning \"Rocky Mountain\".  The range extends
        about 80 km from the north-west to the south-east and is about 40 km wide, spanning a
        territory of 2,585 km2 (998 sq mi). To the north Pirin is separated from Bulgaria\'s highest
        mountain range, the Rila Mountains, by the Predel saddle, while to the south it reaches the
        Slavyanka Mountains. To the west is located the valley of the river Struma and to the east
        the valley of the river Mesta separates it from the Rhodope Mountains. Pirin is dotted with
        more than a hundred glacial lakes and is also the home of Europe\'s southernmost glaciers,
        Snezhnika and Banski Suhodol.  The northern part of the range, which is also the highest one,
        is protected by the Pirin National Park, declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1983.
        Pirin is noted for its rich flora and fauna, as well as for the presence of a number of
        relict species. Much of the area is forested, with some of the best preserved conifer woods
        in Bulgaria, holding important populations of the Balkan endemic species Macedonian pine,
        Bosnian pine and Bulgarian fir. Animals include many species of high conservation value,
        such as brown bear, gray wolf, wildcat, European pine marten, wild boar, red deer, roe deer,
        chamois, etc.  The combination of favourable natural conditions and varied historical
        heritage contribute makes Pirin an important tourist destination. The town of Bansko,
        situated on the north-eastern slopes of the mountain, has grown to be the primary ski and
        winter sports centre in the Balkans. A number of settlements at the foothills of Pirin have
        mineral spring and are spa resorts — Banya, Dobrinishte, Gotse Delchev, Sandanski, etc.
        Melnik at the south-western foothills of the mountain is Bulgaria\'s smallest town and is an
        architectural reserve. Within a few kilometres from the town are the Melnik Earth Pyramids
        and the Rozhen Monastery.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="valyavishki_lakes_pirin">Valyavishki Lakes</string>
    <string name="pirin_valyavishki_lakes">The Valyavishki Lakes (Bulgarian: Валявишки езера) is a
        group of lakes in the northern parts Pirin, southwestern Bulgaria and includes 10 lakes.
        They are amphitheatrically situated in the cirque of the same name. The lakes are glacial
        and lie on a granite bed. They are located between 2,300 and 2,475 m. Their shores are steep
        and rocky. Pine-scrub grows around the lakes due to the high altitude.  Trout is abundant in
        the waters. There have been attempts to introduce the Brook trout into the lakes. The higher
        lakes drain into the lower ones due to their step-like situation. The group is the source of
        the Valyavitsa river which is a main tributary to the Demyanitsa river.  The largest lake by
        area is the Big lake which is located at an altitude of 2379 m. It is 18 meters deep. The
        big lake is 270 m wide and 480 m long with an area of 81,5 decares. The lake is situated in
        the vicinity of the Valyavishki Chukar peak.  The Valyavishki lakes are among the main
        tourist attractions in the area. The closest hut is the Demyanitsa refuge at 2 hour from the
        lakes.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="samodivski_lakes_pirin">Samodivski Lakes</string>
    <string name="pirin_samodivski_lakes">The Samodivski Lakes (Bulgarian: Самодивски езера) is a
        small group of lakes in Pirin, southwestern Bulgaria, part of the larger group of Popovski
        lakes. They are situated very close to each other in a small cirque to the south west of the
        Popovo Lake between the peak Dzhengal, Momin Dvor and Kralev Dvor. They are situated at an
        altitude of 2,373 m, 2,375 m, 2,372 m. The highest has a shape of a boat with size of 75x85
        m and surface of 3,20 decares; the second one resembles a kidney and is longer (100x35 m)
        with area of 2,20 decares; the lowest is also the smallest one with size of 50x20 m and
        surface of only 1 decare. The Samodivski lakes are considered as one of the most beautiful
        in Pirin and with good reason: they are nestled among high rocks, a small stream curves
        between them which even forms a tiny waterfall between the higher lakes. They names derives
        from the folklore beliefs that the wood nymphs gather around at night. According to the
        legend, the area was home of the daughter of the Slavic god Perun. The track between the
        Bezbog refuge and the Tevno Lake passes nearby. There are suitable places for camping.\n
        Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="vihren_pirin">Vihren</string>
    <string name="pirin_vihren">Vihren (Bulgarian: Вихрен) is the highest peak of Bulgaria\'s Pirin
        Mountains. Reaching 2,914 metres (9,560 ft), it is Bulgaria\'s second and the Balkans\'
        third highest, after Musala and Mount Olympus.[2] Although due to the karst topography
        Vihren is deprived of lakes and streams, a number of Pirin\'s lakes are located around the
        peak, as is Europe\'s southernmost glacial mass, the Snezhnika glacielet.[3] Until 1942
        Vihren was known as Eltepe (peak of storms); it was also called Buren (stormy) and
        Malnienosets (lightning-bringer).[4] The UNESCO World Heritage Site Pirin National Park was
        originally known as the Vihren National Park.[5] Vihren is included in the 100 Tourist Sites
        of Bulgaria under № 2.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>
    <string name="melnik_earth_pyramids_pirin">Melnik Earth Pyramids</string>
    <string name="pirin_melnik_earth_pyramids">The Melnik Earth Pyramids are rock formations, known
        as hoodoos, situated at the foothills of the Pirin mountain range in south-western Bulgaria.
        They span an area of 17 km2 near the town of Melnik, Blagoevgrad Province. Reaching a height
        of up to 100 m these sandstone pyramids are shaped in forms, resembling giant mushrooms,
        ancient towers and obelisks. They were formed primarily due to erosion from rainfall and
        bedrock wear. The Melnik Earth Pyramids are a geological phenomenon of global importance
        and were declared a natural landmark in 1960.[1] The rock formations are home to rich flora
        and fauna heavily influenced by the Mediterranian climate. They are popular tourist
        destination not only because of the natural beauty but also due to the cultural sights of
        Melnik and the Rozhen Monastery.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <!-- SOFIA -->
    <string name="sofia">Sofia</string>
    <string name="alexander_nevsky_cathedral_sofia">Alexander Nevsky Cathedral</string>
    <string name="sofia_alexander_nevsky_cathedral">The St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral (Bulgarian:
        Храм-паметник \"Свети Александър Невски\", Hram-pametnik \"Sveti Aleksandar Nevski\") is a
        Bulgarian Orthodox cathedral in Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria. Built in Neo-Byzantine style,
        it serves as the cathedral church of the Patriarch of Bulgaria and it is one of the largest
        Eastern Orthodox cathedrals in the world, as well as one of Sofia\'s symbols and primary
        tourist attractions.[1][2] The St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral in Sofia occupies an area of
        3,170 square metres (34,100 sq ft) and can hold 10,000 people inside.[1][3] It is the second
        -largest cathedral located on the Balkan Peninsula, after the Church of Saint Sava in
        Belgrade.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>
    <string name="monument_unknown_soldier_sofia">Monument to the Unknown Soldier</string>
    <string name="sofia_monument_unknown_soldier">The Monument to the Unknown Soldier (Bulgarian:
        Паметник на Незнайния воин, Pametnik na Neznayniya voin) is a monument in the centre of
        Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria, located just next to the 6th-century Church of St Sophia,
        on 2 Paris Street. The monument commemorates the hundreds of thousands of Bulgarian soldiers
        who died in wars defending their homeland. Ceremonies involving the President of Bulgaria
        and foreign state leaders are often performed here.[1][2]  The monument was designed by
        architect Nikola Nikolov and opened on September 22, 1981, the 1300th anniversary of
        establishment of the Bulgarian state.[3]  The Monument to the Unknown Soldier features an
        eternal flame, turf from Stara Zagora and Shipka Pass, sites of two of the most important
        battles of the Russo-Turkish War of Liberation (the Battle of Stara Zagora and the Battle
        of Shipka Pass), a sculpture of a lion (a national symbol of Bulgaria) by the noted sculptor
        Andrey Nikolov, as well as a stone inscription of a stanza (part of The New Graveyard Above
        Slivnitsa 1885 poem) by the national writer Ivan Vazov:\\n O BULGARIA, FOR YOU THEY DIED,
        ONLY ONE WERE YOU WORTHY OF THEM AND THEY OF YOU WORTHY, O MOTHER, WERE!\n
        Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="central_mineral_baths_sofia">Central Mineral Baths</string>
    <string name="sofia_central_mineral_baths">The Central Mineral Baths (Централна минерална баня,
        Tsentralna mineralna banya) is a landmark in the centre of Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria,
        a city known for the mineral springs in the area. It was built in the early 20th century
        near the former Turkish bath (then destroyed) and was used as the city\'s public baths until
        1986.  Public baths have existed in Sofia since at least the 16th century. During Hans
        Dernschwam visit to Sofia in 1553–1555, the Bohemian traveller noted the presence of 1 large
        bath and 2 smaller baths on either side of the city. Dernschwam described the baths as
        follows: “ \tThe baths are located on the square; there is a big quadrangular building in
        front by the entrance, with a round Greek-style dome on top, like the Pantheon in Rome. It
        is richly covered in white marble … The big water conduits that lead the water into the
        baths are made of potter\'s clay. Each tube is approximately one Viennese cubit long and the
        separate tubes go through each other. They are plastered up like I have seen in Siebenbürgen (
        Transylvania) too, in old buildings in Thorenburg (Turda).[1] \t”  The current Central
        Mineral Baths building was designed in the Vienna Secession style, but integrating typically
        Bulgarian, Byzantine and Eastern Orthodox ornamental elements, by the architects Petko
        Momchilov and Friedrich Grünanger in 1904–1905 and approved on 30 January 1906, as projects
        by an Austrian (in 1889) and a French architect (in 1901) were declined. The raw construction
        was finished in 1908 and a Bulgarian company constructed the complex roof and the mineral
        water conduit. The baths opened on 13 May 1913, but the building was completely finished
        after 2 more years and a garden was arranged in front of the baths. Artists Haralampi Tachev
        and St. Dimitrov designed the building\'s ceramic majolica decoration.[2]  The north wing
        was damaged during the bombing of Sofia in World War II, but was restored several years
        later. The baths continued to work as public baths until 1986, when the building was closed
        due to its bad condition and the possible collapse of the roof. It was subsequently
        partially reconstructed and thoroughly cleaned and accommodates the Sofia Regional
        Historical Museum since September 2015.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="ivan_vazov_theatre_sofia">Ivan Vazov National Theatre</string>
    <string name="sofia_ivan_vazov_theatre">The Ivan Vazov National Theatre (Bulgarian: Народен
        театър „Иван Вазов“, Naroden teatar „Ivan Vazov“) is Bulgaria\'s national theatre, as well
        as the oldest and most authoritative theatre in the country and one of the important
        landmarks of Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria. It is located in the centre of the city, with
        the facade facing the City Garden.  Founded in 1904 by the artists from the Salza i Smyah
        company, it was initially called simply the National Theatre, but before being named after
        the prominent writer Ivan Vazov it also bore the name of Krastyu Sarafov between 1952 and
        1962. Incidentally Vazov\'s play, \"The Outcasts\" was the first to be performed at the
        theatre when it opened. The theatre\'s Neoclassical building, designed by famous Viennese
        theatre architects Hermann Helmer and Ferdinand Fellner, was finished in 1906 and opened on
        3 January 1907. The building was extensively damaged by a fire in 1923 during an anniversary
        celebration, but was reconstructed in 1929 by German architect Martin Dülfer.  A theatrical
        school was established as part of the National Theatre in 1925. The bombing of Sofia in
        World War II caused considerable damage to the building, but it was reconstructed in 1945.
        Another reconstruction followed in 1971–1975, and a €100,000 restoration project was
        implemented in 2006.[1]  The Ivan Vazov National Theatre has a well-equipped main stage with
        750 seats, a smaller 120-seat stage and an additional 70-seat one on the fourth floor.
        The building\'s facade is depicted on the obverse of the Bulgarian 50 levs banknote, issued
        in 1999 and 2006.[2]  The theatre has been host to productions from notable theatre directors
        such as Alexander Morfov who has been the Chief director since 1993.\n
        Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <!-- PLOVDIV -->
    <string name="plovdiv">Plovdiv</string>
    <string name="roman_theatre_plovdiv">Plovdiv Roman theatre</string>
    <string name="plovdiv_roman_theatre">The Roman theatre of Plovdiv (Latin: TEATRUM TRIMONTENSE;
        Bulgarian: Пловдивски античен театър, Plovdivski antichen teatar) is one of the world\'s
        best-preserved ancient theatres, located in the city center of Plovdiv, Bulgaria. It was
        constructed in the 90s of the 1st century AD, probably under the rulership of Emperor
        Domitian. The theatre can host between 5000 and 7000 spectators and it is currently in use.
        The spectator seats are orientated to the south, towards the ancient city in the lowland
        and the Rhodope Mountains. In outline, the theatre is a semi-circle with an outer diameter
        of 82 meters. The theatre itself is divided into the seating section (auditorium) and the
        stage (orchestra). The auditorium, the area in which people gathered, is hollowed out of a
        hill or slope, while the outer radian seats required structural support and solid retaining
        walls. The auditorium was not roofed. The spectator seats (cavea) surround the stage – the
        orchestra – which has the shape of a horseshoe, 26.64 meters long, includes 28 concentric
        rows of marble seats, divided into two tiers by an aisle (diazoma). The upper part of the
        tiers is interrupted by narrow radial stairways, which divide the cavea into wedge-shaped
        sectors (kerkides). The theatre also has a podium, which supports the columns of the scaenae

        frons.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>
    <string name="old_town_plovdiv">Old Town Plovdiv</string>
    <string name="plovdiv_old_town">The old town in Plovdiv is an architectural and historical
        reserve located on three of Plovdiv\'s hills: Nebet Tepe, Dzhambaz Tepe and Taksim Tepe.
        The complex has been formed as a result of the long sequence of habitation from prehistoric
        times to present day and combines the culture and architecture from Antiquity, Middle Ages
        and Bulgarian revival. The old town in Plovdiv is included in UNESCO World Heritage tentative
        list since 2004. Balabanov house is emblematic for the cultural life in Plovdiv. It hosts
        numerous events such as theatrical performances, concerts, exhibitions, literature readings.
        The house was built in the 19th century near St. Constantine and Elena square. The wide
        entrance door leads to a long, high-ceiling vestibule around which the residential and
        commercial premises are situated. An inner staircase leads to a large, glazed hall with
        richly ornamented carved-wood ceiling on the second floor. The hall is surrounded by four
        rooms decorated with restored antique furniture, fabrics and other items demonstrating the
        taste of the rich citizens of Plovdiv in the 19th century.\n
        Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="old_school_bazaar_plovdiv">Old Style Bazar</string>
    <string name="plovdiv_old_school_bazaar">The trapezoid is named after the fifteenth century when
        two narrow market spaces, pressed from everywhere with shops called \"Un Trap\" and \"Buyuk
        Trap\", call the neighborhood around. This is a craft workshop in Plovdiv, and in 1652 there
        were 880 shops. Towards the beginning of the 20th century, Trapani is the commercial heart
        of the city. There is international trade, which plays a key role in maintaining
        craftsmanship in the region. [1] Among the most impressive buildings in the neighborhood
        are Kurshumhan, which houses the Abanje\'s Shanabad House and the large, uninhabited,
        rectangular one-story 500-square-meter building where merchants pick up their goods. The
        seminars of the various associations are located around the deserts, and the names of some
        of the streets (preserved today) show where the shops for all crafts - \"Zhelezarska\",
        \"Zlatarska\", \"Abadjiiska\", \"Kozhuharska\"  In 1906 a fire broke out in Plovdiv and a
        large part of the buildings in the Kapana were destroyed. In the 70\'s of the twentieth
        century, a plan for the construction of a large shopping center was adopted instead of the
        craft quarters. Detailed plans and designs of individual buildings are being developed,
        commencement of the expropriation of the properties and preparation for the demolition of
        the first buildings. [2] The collective tobacco created during this time saved the
        neighborhood from total destruction by convincing architects and institutions that Trap is
        an exclusive place that makes sense to preserve. A document by Antoaneta Topalova, a call
        for the preservation of the neighborhood and its buildings, was published in the \"Fatherland
        Voice\" newspaper in Plovdiv.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>

    <string name="city_from_sky_plovdiv">Plovdiv from sky</string>
    <string name="plovdiv_city">Plovdiv (Bulgarian: Пловдив, pronounced [ˈpɫovdif]) is the second-
        largest city in Bulgaria, with a city population of 341,000 as of 2015 and 675,000 in the
        greater metropolitan area. It is an important economic, transport, cultural, and educational
        center. There is evidence of habitation in Plovdiv dating back to the 6th millennium BCE,
        when the first Neolithic settlements were established; it is said to be one of the oldest
        cities in Europe.[4][5][6]  During most of its recorded history, Plovdiv was known in the
        West by the name Philippopolis (Greek: Φιλιππούπολις; Turkish: Filibe; \"Philip\'s Town\")
        after Philip II of Macedon conquered the city in the 4th century BCE. The city was originally
        a Thracian settlement[6] and subsequently was invaded by Persians, Greeks, Celts, Romans,
        Goths, Huns, Bulgars, Slavs, Rus people, Crusaders, and Turks. On 4 January 1878, Plovdiv
        was liberated from Ottoman rule by the Russian army. It remained within the borders of
        Bulgaria until July of the same year, when it became the capital of the autonomous Ottoman
        region of Eastern Rumelia. In 1885, Plovdiv and Eastern Rumelia joined Bulgaria.  Plovdiv is
        situated in a fertile region of south-central Bulgaria on the two banks of the Maritsa River.
        The city has historically developed on seven syenite hills, some of which are 250 metres
        (820 feet) high. Because of these hills, Plovdiv is often referred to in Bulgaria as \"The
        City of the Seven Hills\".  Plovdiv is host to a huge variety of cultural events such as the
        International Fair Plovdiv, the international theatrical festival \"A stage on a crossroad\",
        the TV festival \"The golden chest,\" and many more novel festivals, such as Night/Plovdiv in
        September, Kapana Fest, and Opera Open. There are many preserved ruins such as the ancient
        Plovdiv Roman theatre, a Roman odeon, a Roman aqueduct, the Plovdiv Roman Stadium, the
        archaeological complex Eirene, and others.  The oldest American educational institution
        outside the United States, the American College of Sofia, was founded in Plovdiv in 1860 and
        later moved to Sofia.  On 5 September 2014, Plovdiv was selected as the Bulgarian host of
        the European Capital of Culture 2019.[7] This happened with the help of the Municipal
        Foundation \"Plovdiv 2019″, a non-government organization, which was established in 2011 by
        Plovdiv\'s City Council whose main objectives were to develop and to prepare Plovdiv\'s bid

        book for European Capital of Culture in 2019.\n Released under CC-BY-SA</string>
    <string name="grid">grid</string>
    <string name="varna">Varna</string>

    <!-- Odrysian_Kingdom -->
    <string name="by_alexikoua_cc_by_sa_3_0">By Alexikoua, CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="odrysian_kingdom_title">Odrysian kingdom\n460 BC – 46 AD</string>
    <string name="odrysian_kingdom_detail">The Odrysian Kingdom, oʊˈdrɪʒən Ancient Greek:
        Βασίλειον Ὀδρυσῶν Latin Regnum Odrysium was a state union of over 40 Thracian tribes
        and 22 kingdoms that existed between the 5th century BC and the 1st century AD.</string>

    <string name="by_klearchos_kapoutsis">Klearchos Kapoutsis, CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="roman_period">Roman period\n46–681 BC</string>
    <string name="roman_period_detail">Due to the rural nature of the local population, Roman
        control of the region remained weak. In the 5th century, Attila\'s Huns attacked the
        territories of today\'s Bulgaria and pillaged many Roman settlements. By the end of the
        6th century, Avars organized regular incursions into northern Bulgaria, which were a prelude
        to the en masse arrival of the Slavs.</string>

    <string name="seikoen">SeikoEn, CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="dark_ages">Dark Ages\n6th–7th cent</string>
    <string name="dark_ages_detail">The Slavs emerged from their original homeland in the early 6th
        century and spread to most of eastern Central Europe, Eastern Europe and the Balkans, thus
        forming three main branches - the West Slavs, the East Slavs and the South Slavs. The
        easternmost South Slavs settled on the territory of modern Bulgaria during the 6th century.
        Most of the Thracians were eventually Hellenized or Romanized, with the last remnants
        surviving in remote areas until the 5th century.A portion of the eastern South Slavs
        assimilated most of them, before the Bulgar élite incorporated these peoples into the
        First Bulgarian Empire.</string>

    <string name="kandi">Kandi, CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="first_bulgarian_empire">First Bulgarian Empire\n681–1018 BC</string>
    <string name="first_bulgarian_empire_detail">The First Bulgarian Empire (Old Bulgarian: ц︢рьство
        бл︢гарское, ts\'rstvo bl\'garskoe) was a medieval Bulgarian state that existed in southeastern
        Europe between the 7th and 11th centuries AD. It was founded circa 681 when Bulgar tribes
        led by Asparukh moved to the north-eastern Balkans. There they secured Byzantine recognition
        of their right to settle south of the Danube by defeating – possibly with the help of local
        South Slavic tribes – the Byzantine army led by Constantine IV. At the height of its power,
        Bulgaria spread from the Danube Bend to the Black Sea and from the Dnieper River to the
        Adriatic Sea.</string>

    <string name="nerdyxsk">NerdyNSK, CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="byzantine_bulgaria">Byzantine Bulgaria\n1018–1185</string>
    <string name="byzantine_bulgaria_detail">The Theme of Bulgaria was a province of the Byzantine
        Empire established by Emperor Basil II after the conquest of Bulgaria in 1018. Its capital
        was Skopje and it was governed by a strategos.  Initially the Byzantine emperor Basil II
        issued an order that the tax system of the subdued Bulgarian kingdom continue to be applied
        in the annexed Bulgarian lands. The Bulgarian patriarchate was downgraded to an archbishopric
        called Archbishopric of Ohrid, that retained an autocephalous status.</string>

    <string name="by_kandi_cc_by_sa_3_0"> By Kandi CC BY-SA 3.0</string>
    <string name="second_blgarian_empire">econd Bulgarian Empire\n1185–1396</string>
    <string name="second_blgarian_empire_detail">The Second Bulgarian Empire (Bulgarian: Второ
        българско царство, Vtorо Bălgarskо Tsarstvo) was a medieval Bulgarian state that existed
        between 1185 and 1396.[2] A successor to the First Bulgarian Empire, it reached the peak of
        its power under Tsars Kaloyan and Ivan Asen II before gradually being conquered by the
        Ottomans in the late 14th and early 15th centuries. It was succeeded by the Principality and
        later Kingdom of Bulgaria in 1878.</string>

    <string name="ottoman_license" >Public Domain</string>
    <string name="ottoman_bulgaria">Ottoman Bulgaria\n1396–1878</string>
    <string name="ottoman_bulgaria_detail">The history of Ottoman Bulgaria spans nearly 500 years,
        from the conquest by the Ottoman Empire of the smaller kingdoms emerging from the
        disintegrating Second Bulgarian Empire in the late 14th century, to the Liberation of Bulgaria
        in 1878. As a result of the Russo-Turkish War (1877–1878), the Principality of Bulgaria,
        a self-governing Ottoman vassal state that was functionally independent, was created. In
        1885 the autonomous province of Eastern Rumelia came under the control of the Bulgarian Tsar.
        Bulgaria declared independence in 1908.</string>

    <string name="ac_ferdinand_license">Public Domain</string>
    <string name="third_bulgarian_state">Third Bulgarian State\n1878–present</string>
    <string name="third_bulgarian_state_detail">After the Russo-Turkish War, an autonomous Bulgarian
        state was created within the Ottoman Empire by the Treaty of Berlin in 1878. Although
        remaining under Ottoman sovereignty, it functioned independently, taking Alexander of
        Battenberg as its first prince. In 1885 it took control of the still-Ottoman Eastern
        Rumelia, officially under a personal union. Following the abdication of Alexander, Ferdinand
        I was elected prince in 1887. Full independence was declared in 1908.</string>
    <string name="cities_page">Cities</string>
    <string name="history_page">History</string>

</resources>
